<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Campinhos.pt</title>
    <link>http://campinhos.pt/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://campinhos.pt/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Jo達o Campinhos personal blog about web development</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 16:21:43 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 16:21:43 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update & Projects</title>
      <link>http://campinhos.pt/2013/03/Update-and-Projects</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 12:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jo達o Campinhos</author>
      <guid>http://campinhos.pt/2013/03/Update-and-Projects</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I should write here more often. It's actually quite easy to find a interesting subject but I tend to have a hard time starting the actual post. The lack of posts gives the impression that I forgot my project of creating 12 things on 2013, but so far I've done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My website. it was just a blank page with my name on it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A CSS framework available &lt;a href=&quot;http://campinhos.pt/Tophat/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Markdown &lt;a href=&quot;http://campinhos.pt/words/&quot;&gt;text editor&lt;/a&gt; that uses some crazy HTML5 API's&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Three months, three projects. So far so good right? But since I don't have the time I thought I would, the actual quality of my side projects are not top notch like I wanted them to be. Some things were rushed and some features I couldn't build on time and that reflects on the actual product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's why in this month (April) I'm not going to develop anything. Instead I'm going to improve what I already created:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;April To-do list&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my website and blog (write some more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officially launch Tophat.css and finish those damn docs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some more features to words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update some old projects and open source them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;in addiction to all of that, and since I'm putting more love and care into my stuff, I'm also going to put my projects on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;hacker news&lt;/a&gt; and other sources to get some feedback. I'm only doing that when I'm 100% sure of the quality of my work so I may delay that a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disqus</title>
      <link>http://campinhos.pt/2013/02/Disqus</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 15:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jo達o Campinhos</author>
      <guid>http://campinhos.pt/2013/02/Disqus</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The to do list for my blog is not big, but it does have some important stuff that needs to be done. &lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; is a nice example.
This is really important to me because since I don't receive much feedback, every piece of it counts. I also think that comments can promote discussion, which is always good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Disqus VS Branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not sure about wether I should use &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://branch.com/&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt; but, after some research my decision was quite easy to make.
Although both Disqus and Branch are fairly easy to implement, and they both have a nice design, Branch isn't quite appropriate for blogs. At least not as a comment system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branch has its strenghts, but for my particular case I decided to go with Disqus because it's a more traditional system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;About February&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developing my own css framework. It will only be a draft with very few features but I already have some things that I want to add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reset (Probably a custom version of normalize.css)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typography (basic stuff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grid (responsive and not responsive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some nice abstractions like &lt;code&gt;nav&lt;/code&gt; and other stuff that might come in handy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design (but with an easy way to turn it off)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, as you can see, for now it will be some basic stuff useful for my own projects. To be honest, if I wanted a framework full of features, I would use &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com/&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt; right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm using &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;SASS&lt;/a&gt; because it's awesome, and i'm naming it &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joaocampinhos/Tophat&quot;&gt;Tophat&lt;/a&gt; because I like top hats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Beginning</title>
      <link>http://campinhos.pt/2013/01/A-New-beginning</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Jo達o Campinhos</author>
      <guid>http://campinhos.pt/2013/01/A-New-beginning</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It's 2013 and I need to be more proactive. I decided to create something different each month, no matter what or with which technology. Those are the rules and for &lt;strong&gt;January&lt;/strong&gt; I planned a somewhat big redesign of my personal page. I chose Jekyll to the engine because it will allow me to create something quickly while keeping it hosted on Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem was that in January I was busy with my final exams, and of course I needed to study for all of them. I ended up not having the time that I wanted but I still managed to create something that I really enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Time vs Optimization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things in the code will look amateur. One thing that you'll notice is the active menu handling. It's hardcoded and ugly, but I didn't have the time to rethink it in a better way. It's hard for me to put something online that I'm not 100% happy with but I said that I would finish it in one month and I did it. The entire to-do list is available on Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Designing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not a designer. I don't have the knowledge nor the skills to design. I'm working on that, reading some books and doing some experiments, but I don't think that I will be ready soon. Although I think I did a nice job with my redesign, I know that it's not polished, and I'm planning to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Windows factor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web development on windows. One might say that it's the same, but I was so used to working on a unix environment that I felt that I spent a lot of time on stupid things. My Windows environment is not perfect (I'm not a fan of powershell). I'm pretty happy with windows stability so far, so I think that I will get used to working on windows pretty soon (Although OSX is still my favorite).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;But your CSS is a mess&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed it is. I wanted to create something really beautiful and DRY but I didn't have enough time. I thought about using a framework but I had a better idea: Instead of creating my css on top of a framework, I created my super ugly css in a couple of hours and I will create my own framework from scratch in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;February&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's right, my project for the upcoming month is to create a &lt;strong&gt;css framework&lt;/strong&gt; for myself to use it like a bootstrap for everything front-end related. The problem is that every framework is built for you to work on top of that. My main objective is to create something that will allow me to modify it and extend it as I need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update:&lt;/strong&gt; I am having some issues with the paginator feature of Jekyll so I decided to disable it for now. Don't know the problem yet but for now it should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
